What I believe history will record
that America's challenge of today
has forged man's destiny for tomorrow.
And is we leave.
We leave as we came.
And God willing, as we still return,
Godspeed the crew of Apollo 17.
Ten, nine, eight, seven.
Ignition sequence started.
All engines are started.
We have ignition.
Two, one, zero. We have liftoff.
17 Houston. You said you were a go
for orbit. Go for orbit.
America. Houston, this is America.
You can breathe easier.
America has arrived at station
for the challenge ahead.
Oh. Are we coming in? Oh, baby.
ok, Houston the Challenger has landed.
We'd like to dedicate
the first step of Apollo 17
to all those who made it possible.
Oh, my gully
unbelievable!
That's got to be one of the most
proud moments of my life, I guarantee you.
The words, are here man completed
his first exploration on the Moon
December 1972 A.D., May the spirit of peace
in which we came
be reflected in the lives of all mankind.
When we look back at the Apollo program,
I don't think anyone privately
to publicly say to themselves
that this truly has really been
a beginning. A beginning of
mans really first venture
out into deep space
and once there is a beginning.
There is a continuation.
A trip to Mars may not be
for ten years, a decade.
It may not be till the end of the century.
But I personally have faith
that it will happen.
And I think that the nature of mankind.
just press on. That's why I believe
that we about 17 years at the beginning.
But the whole Apollo program and really
the beginning of what's come the future.
God speed and God bless you all.